a beast in the gym the rogue ohio bar
may be the next addition that you need
for your home gym it's able to
accommodate even the most elite level
weight lifters with the knurling that
won't absolutely destroy your hands in
the process
plus it features a tensile strength
rating of 190 000 psi
putting it in an elite category
[Music]
yo everyone it's jake back again in the
barbing garage gym and in for review
today i have the rogue ohio bar in this
video i'm gonna walk you through all the
details of this bar the price some pros
and cons and as always who should and
who should not buy this barbell but
before we get started it's worth
mentioning we have reviewed a ton of
barbells on barbin.com just go ahead and
search barbind best barbells and find
out for yourself which one takes home
the crown
[Music]
what do i like about the rogue ohio bar
well for one it comes in multiple
options but the one we have here today
for you guys is the stainless steel
version the head honcho when it comes to
fighting off rust
two for somebody who likes to power
clean a lot you'll love the fact this
bar
does not come with a center knurling
meaning your skin will be less irritated
over time
and a feature so nice that i had to name
it twice the tensile strength rating of
this barbell is 190 000 psi meaning you
can put the heaviest of weight on here
and you do not have to worry about it
bending or breaking
[Music]
per usual there could be some potential
cons with this bar which you might not
like start with the knurling here as i
mentioned it is a little bit on the
moderate side and thanks to the
stainless steel it does have a nice grip
but if you're somebody with rough hands
or maybe you just want an extra firm
grip you might need to look for a
different option and it's also worth
noting that the sleeves on this bar do
have a grooved pattern which might be
nice in terms of keeping your weight
plates in place but at the same time
they do have a little bit of a zip noise
when you're loading and unloading the
bar while they do have bronze bushings
that allow the bar to spin during your
lifts
i couldn't help but notice they don't
spin as freely as some competitor bars
do but this also could only be the case
in our individual bar
[Music]
since there are multiple versions of the
rogue ohio bar there's also different
pricing options so for the stainless
steel bar you're looking at around 370
dollars and i know that's a little high
but you're also buying the high quality
product that this is which could be the
last barbell you ever buy and the chrome
sleeves come standard with the stainless
steel but you can also upgrade those two
stainless steel sleeves that'll be an
additional 95
bringing your total to about 460 465.
once you factor in shipping you're
looking at around 530 as your total
but
rogue also allows you to use pay later
through paypal which will divide
everything up into four interest-free
payments of around 130
since i mentioned the other versions of
this bar it's also worth noting the
pricings for those versions so the black
zinc and the e-coat are going to run you
around 300
the black oxide is about 320 and the
custom bar is around 350
now since these prices are relatively
similar it may be worth going for the
stainless steel option since it is the
highest quality
since there are multiple versions of the
rogue ohio bar the build is going to
differ depending on which one you decide
to go with we have the stainless steel
version in front of you today which does
feature bronze bushings in the sleeves
allowing them to spin which is very nice
when you're trying to power clean
also with the sleeves they're a little
over 16 inches and the diameter of this
bar is around 28 and a half millimeters
which is about the same size as an
olympic barbell it's also worth noting
you can put up to 1
260 pounds on this barbell and the
tensile strength is
000 psi let's dig into some of the
features now of the rogue ohio bar the
knurling on this bar is a volcano
pattern and it's not overly aggressive
meaning it's a good option for almost
every weight lifter out there there is
no center knurling on this bar so
anybody trying to do an olympic style
lift you're gonna love that and the
sleeves have a grooved pattern which may
help your plates stay in place longer
while it also has bronze bushings
allowing the bar to spin for those
olympic style lifts
since this bar is stainless steel it's
gonna fight off rust higher than any of
the other options available and with
this stainless steel bar you can choose
between either chrome or stainless steel
sleeves
[Music]
all right so we're going to walk you
through the rogue ohio bar now as you
can see this is a nice stainless steel
bar it's going to really fight off that
rust also
notice there's no center knurling making
it ideal for those power cleans any
olympic style lifting really and as we
also mentioned this does feature a
volcano pattern as you can see you have
your standard double knurl marks right
here
bronze bushings right here will really
allow this sleeve to spin while you are
performing those power cleans
and also
there is a groove pattern right here and
as you can hear
a little bit of a zip right there when
you're loading and unloading your weight
that zip may get annoying to some people
but you do have a better chance of
keeping your plates locked in
[Music]
okay so who should buy this barbell
that's a very good question so if you're
new to weightlifting you're gonna love
the fact that the knurling on this bar
it's more on the moderate side meaning
your hands shouldn't get torn up in the
process of working out and since this is
a stainless steel version of this bar
you're gonna have better luck with this
one fighting off rust than the other
options and three this does have a
tensile strength rating of 190 000 psi
meaning it's a good fit for virtually
every level weight lifter on the flip
side of things if you're somebody
looking for a super firm grip on your
barbell this may not be the one for you
while it does have a good grip thanks to
that stainless steel there are other
options out there that might feel better
in your hands
two
with the groove pattern on the sleeves
that keep your plates locked in it could
lead to a zip noise when you're loading
and unloading that you may not like
and you know let's not forget this is an
expensive barbell and there are other
cheaper options out there but with this
one you're buying quality meaning it
could be the last barbell that you ever
need to buy
well that about wraps up today's video
of the rogue ohio bar once again we
reviewed the stainless steel version of
this bar while there are other options
available i personally believe this is
the best one out of all of those it's a
beast in the weight room and thanks to
its tensile strength of 190 000 psi it's
going to handle almost any weight you
throw at it so whether you're squatting
benching power cleaning dead lifting
whatever it may be
rogue ohio bars got your back as always
thanks for watching i hope this video
helped you out in your pursuit for your
next barbell
i'm gonna go throw some weight around
but in the meantime keep an eye out for
my next video head over to barban.com to
read up more about this bar just search
barbind rogue ohio bar review and it'll
pull right up for you see you next time
[Music]
you